At the nail level, the normal angulation, which is approximately
在指甲层面，正常的角度大约是
165 degrees.
165度。
If there is an inversion, it can actually indicate a sign of pulmonary failure.
如果角度反转，这实际上可能表明肺功能衰竭的迹象。
So, nails like these, which are often brittle, bitten.
那么像这样经常易碎、被咬的指甲。
These are nervous people or children who are bored.
这是紧张的人或是感到无聊的孩子。
You also have a nail where you see horizontal lines.
你还会看到指甲上有水平线。
This is a...
这是一种...
difficulty with nutrient absorption.
营养吸收方面的困难。
Then you have vertical lines
然后你还会看到垂直线
of absorption at the intestinal level.
肠道吸收方面。
You are not absorbing correctly.
你没有正确吸收。
Then sometimes you have small dots,
然后你有时会看到小点，
like that, small dots.
像这样的小点。
So they can be linked to...
那么它们可能与...
Because I hit myself, it makes a small dot.
因为我敲击了，就会形成一个小点。
Each finger represents a specific organ.
每个手指代表一个特定的器官。
And if it's these small dots,
如果是这些小点，
it's mineral deficiencies or losses.
这是矿物质缺乏或流失。
Mainly zinc, iron,
主要是锌、铁，
and copper, but especially zinc and copper. Why? For example, if I have an infection
和铜，但尤其是锌和铜。为什么呢？例如，如果我感染了
of
肠道
an intestinal type or if I have a pulmonary type infection, I will use my minerals
感染，或者如果我患有肺部感染，我会使用我的矿物质。
and where
那么它们在哪里
are my minerals found? Well, they are found up there in my bones and in
我的矿物质在哪里呢？它们就在我的骨骼和
my nails, and I will go get my reserves and I will use them to
我的指甲里。我会去提取我的储备，并用它们来
bring my white blood cells
将我的白细胞带到
to the right place. Once you have eliminated the infection through your white blood cell system,
正确的位置。一旦你的白细胞系统清除了感染，
well, the mineral leaves with it.
那么矿物质也会随之离开。
Hence the importance, to have a good immune system, of having a good mineral system.
因此，为了拥有良好的免疫系统，拥有良好的矿物质系统至关重要。
So, nails like these, where there is an inversion, indicate a fragile lung and heart.
那么像这样有反转的指甲，表明肺和心脏脆弱。
Sometimes, on the nails, you really have a very significant stop like that.
有时，你会发现指甲上出现非常明显的生长停滞。
Either it's a fungus, so an immune deficiency, or it's really a deep metabolic problem
要么是真菌感染，即免疫缺陷，要么是真正的深层代谢问题
that is expressing itself.
所表现出来的。
Sometimes spoon-shaped nails can express an absorption or storage problem.
有时出现勺状甲，可能表明存在吸收或储存问题，或
to do with a too rapid degradation of red blood cells. If there is bulging, it is
储存问题。
cardiac
与红细胞降解过快有关。如果出现隆起（杵状指），则表明是
or Vasquez's disease. The absence of a lunula expresses a lack of vitality. It's the
心脏问题
little
或瓦克斯病。甲半月缺失表明活力不足。它是指
white part here. I take someone's nail and you will
小小的
press on your nail. I press,
这里的小白点。我拿起某人的指甲，然后你会
it whitens and then it comes back. No problem with the blood, no problem with anemia.
按压你的指甲。我按压，
However, not enough lunula. A yellow nail is a sign of a fresh liver.
它变白然后迅速恢复。血液方面没有问题，没有贫血问题。
while a blue nail is a sign of a fragile heart or lung symptom.
相反，甲半月不足。黄指甲是肝脏问题的迹象。
If the lunula is bluish, be careful, it can indicate a disturbed liver.
而蓝指甲是心脏或肺部脆弱的症状。
If the lunula is red, it is an early sign of a possible heart problem,
如果甲半月呈蓝色，请注意，这可能表明肝脏功能紊乱。
especially if the tip of the tongue is very red.
如果甲半月呈红色，这可能是心脏问题的早期迹象，
Hands or bodies that are clammy, you take them in your hand,
特别是如果舌尖非常红。
they are cold and clammy. What is it?
那些手或身体潮湿的人，你握住他们的手，
It indicates a thyroid imbalance, or
它们是冰冷潮湿的。这是什么？
If it's someone who is, for example, thin with very bulging eyes
这表明是甲状腺失衡，或者是
and clammy hands, it's a thyroid imbalance.
如果是某人，例如，消瘦且眼睛明显突出，
Always check the adrenals, don't forget.
并且双手潮湿，那就是甲状腺失衡。
Maybe his adrenals are empty and he can't convert his T3 to T4.
务必检查肾上腺，不要忘记。
Remember to think about the thyroid-adrenal tandem or a hepatic problem of
也许他的肾上腺功能耗竭，无法将T3转化为T4。
congestive type.
务必考虑甲状腺-肾上腺轴或肝脏问题，
People who are sensitive to cold, the exhaustion of ancestral kidney energy
充血型的。
or...
那些畏寒的人，是肾脏先天之气耗竭
also a thyroid problem, hypothyroidism.
或...
The hair.
也可能是甲状腺问题，即甲状腺功能减退。
Gray hair in a very young person can indicate an imbalance in the absorption
头发。
of certain amino acids.
年轻人头发灰白，这可能表明吸收功能失衡。
So check what's happening in the intestines and liver.
某些氨基酸的吸收失衡。
But what's interesting is to observe in some people the discoloration
因此，应检查肠道和肝脏的功能。
of the eyebrows.
但有趣的是，在某些人身上观察到色素减退
It's a sign of food or other allergies.
在眉毛处。